You’re getting pretty good, Ryota.
You can already do those moves?
I’m gonna be a starter.
Really? Alright.
I will become...
... the captain of this house, Mom.
Listen Ryota...
It’s up to us to support Mom now.
I’ll be the captain...
... and you’ll be the co-captain.
I’m counting on you Ryota.
If you wanna be a starter
then I’ll treat you like one.
This is a one-on-one.
Don’t turn your back so easily!
That’s just asking for trouble!
You gotta get past me.
Scared? You gotta be brave.
I’m always like this too
my heart pounds like crazy
That’s why...
I have to pretend that I’m fine.
Foul!
No foul!
The real fight comes after the fall, Ryota!
That’s right!
Come at me!
Don’t run away!
You tried hard.
You did well.
Don’t ever forget this.
Sota…
Let’s play again.
Alright, you’re on.
Hey!
Sota!
Let’s play one-on-one!
Sorry, I promised them I’d go.
You said we’d play, one more round!
We’ll play again tomorrow.
Then let me come along!
No, you’re still too young.
Stay and work on your dribble.
You wanna be a starter, right?
What the heck!
You said we were going to play one-on-one!
You were lying about playing again!
Big liar! Stupid Sota!
Dummy! Idiot!
Stupid dumb weenie!
DON’T COME BACK AGAIN!
Here I go.
Kanagawa Prefecture
Shohoku High School
Sannoh Kogyo High School
Akita Prefecture
Alright!
Yes!
He’s going this hard already?
Hey!
Nobe!
What’s the matter Ryo?
Nothing, I can’t believe it went in...
It’s all the same two points, yo.
Yo?
Shohoku
Sannoh
Fukatsu!
Good job!
Good job, good job, Fukatsu!
Oh crap, what’s with this vibe?
How many members are there?
Famous schools are wild.
Compared to them, we’re so mismatched...
Sister.
Friends.
A rival gang.
Defense! Defense!
We really should have made matching shirts.
No way, why would I match with you guys?
Hanamichi, you’re in the way! Cut in!
With a total newbie like Hanamichi out there,
it’s like “Sorry about the redhead”...
What a clown...
Hey, hey, hey!
Somehow I feel like a parent watching.
I understand.
What are you talking about?
Go cheer them on!
MICCHAN!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Whoa!!
Nice one, nice one, Mitsui!
Oh my.
Those guys aren’t playing nice...
OK, but Mitsui is in peak form today, Sannoh.
Alright!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Nice!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Whoa, that’s impressive.
Shohoku
Gorilla Dunk!
Okay, get on defense, let’s stop this shot.
Yeah!
This guy…
If you keep moving like that
you’ll wear yourself out first.
I’m a genius…?
Shohoku
No one else in Japan can make a drive that clean.
Number one in Japan?
Awesome...!
There is someone…!
Do your job better!
Defense! Defense!
The reigning champ Sannoh.
This is the best guard in Japan.
Feared by all other guards in Japan.
Don’t back down, Miyagi!
I’m not!
I’ll go against you all 40 minutes, bastard!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Tourney Cup
15th Mini-Basket
Boys’
Division
Number 2!
Run, run!
Kaoru, come to the front, there’s a seat!
Thank you.
Good thing you made it, we were waiting for you.
Oh my!
Yay! Ryota!
Nice pass!
Nice shot.
Ryota is looking sharper than usual today!
Must be because you’re here.
Go!
Number seven plays well, although he’s short.
It’s that kid, who died a few years ago.
That Miyagi Sota’s younger brother.
Oh! He used to wear the same number 7.
That kid was something else.
So he died?
From an accident at sea, apparently.
That’s not true
Sota is living on a small far-away island right now.
Anna!
I’m sorry.
Second half, start!
Number 7!
Number 15!
Number 6!
Don’t worry about it!
I played against your brother.
That time, I lost real bad against him.
Turns out the little brother ain’t much.
You can do it!
Ryota! Be strong!
Leave it to me!
Ryota!
Ryota you can do it!
Let’s go!
Don’t give up!
Well...
What a letdown, he’s nothing like his brother.
Looks like he can’t replace his brother after all.
Oh, I thought I should tidy up a bit.
This house... let’s move somewhere else.
You don’t have to use the same number just because you’re brothers.
Let’s change it.
Number seven is fine.
What are you—
Get out of here!
Take that off, you have your own clothes!
Stop it! Stop it!
Looks like he can’t replace his brother after all.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Start of the second half.
From here on it’ll be a different match.
Whoa, Sawakita!
A three?
Shohoku
Sannoh
It’s a three!
It’s alright, let’s turn it around!
OK!
A full-court press?
Bastard!
We’ll decide the game within three minutes of the second half.
Miyagi, pass it!
These guys are pushing dammit!
Ouch!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Hey!
Uh oh.
That’s rough.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Again?
What the hell are you doing?
Hurry and give me the ball!
Don’t fuck with me!
Offense, charging!
Now introduce yourself to the class.
Miyagi Ryota.
Starting today, Ryota will be joining our class.
What’s his deal?
He’s so quiet.
Since he just moved from Okinawa
he’s still not familiar with things here, therefore…
Don’t get too full of yourself.
Hey you!
Go play with that ball somewhere else!
Shut up!
Come on, we’re short one person.
You wanna ask him to join?
He seems kinda hard to approach...
Let’s take a break.
Okay.
You in elementary?
I’m in middle school.
You won’t get through by showing off moves.
Put on some pressure, come on.
Giving up already?
You’re wasting those moves just playing alone.
Micchan!
Let’s play again.
Actually try to win next time.
Shut up!
What are you doing? I still haven’t touched the ball!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Shall we take a 20-point lead?
For a newcomer like Shohoku...
...that should destroy their spirits.
5 seconds left.
Hurry!
10 seconds, get it out there!
Damn!
That pass sucked!
Rukawa go back, help them out!
Basket counts! One free throw.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Timeout, red team!
Dickhead Ryo!
I still haven’t touched the ball once!
Let’s take 30 seconds to breathe.
If I were Sannoh, I would keep up the full-court press.
Until it’s been torn down...
...or until the opponent’s spirit is completely broken.
This moment is crucial
Shohoku can’t counter against our full-court press
We must attack now.
Yes!
But we won’t break.
Mitsui, Rukawa...
Yes.
I want you both to run ahead.
Miyagi...
Yes.
This is your stage.
What about me, pops?
The genius Sakuragi?
I want you to turn toward the basket
And run.
Got it.
Ryota!
Give me your hand.
Red team, hurry up.
What are you doing?
Go act like your usual cocky self.
Now it’s a 15-point lead!
They’re going for Miyagi again!
Leave him alone!
Sawakita, the ball yo!
He’s fast yo!
He’s through!
If we’re talking speed, I’m number one—
—yo!
Yes! Press broken!
3 on 2!
We’ll change the flow of the game here!
For real?!
Finally touched the ball...
...turnaround training camp shot!
Idiot!
Saved it!
One shot, let’s take one!
Kawata...
Nice!
He got inside!
No, he doesn’t have an angle!
Nice defense!
Nice!
Nice one Kawata, nice one Kawata!
Will I be able to beat this guy?
Nice one, nice one, Kawata!
You can do it, Akagi!
Let’s go!
That attack pattern, we already know it.
We know that one, too.
Not good.
Shohoku
Sannoh
They’re leading by 20!
Sannoh! Sannoh!
Wow! Sannoh is awesome!
A 20-point gap...
One basket, one basket at a time!
Ichino, look at Mitsui...
The result of your defense in the first half is showing.
Like a gut punch.
Go ahead yo.
His jump shots rarely go in...
They saw through Ryota’s weakness!
Shit! No choice but to use the Secret Weapon Sakuragi.
Let’s go Beanpole!
Secret weapon?
Hoh!
Sakuragi!
Hoh.
Double dribble.
Oh shit!
What a newbie!
You, stop messing around or I’ll kill you.
Shut up asshole! Be quiet.
Eight minutes and not a single basket!
We have to score at least one.
Hey.
Hey hey!
Pass him!
This guy...
...has no openings.
Rukawa, be careful!
Stop hogging it number 11!
Boss! Please!
We can’t lose this match.
Hey!
What?
Timeout!
A no-name team like us got this far
because we’re strong under the basket.
When Boss is fighting hard, everyone’s lively.
Is this it?
Defense, defense!
Defense is about spirit.
Get loud!
Ah, so intense.
Miyagi!
Say something, don’t play in silence.
Talk!
Next group.
I’m not that type of player.
Miyagi!
Was it necessary to use such a fancy pass just now?
Your play style is too flashy!
Huh?!
So much nagging…
Just ignore him, you’ll get used to it.
That pass is quicker.
The defense can’t react against it.
But I didn’t think even my own teammate couldn’t react to it.
What did you say?
I can’t stand him, I seriously can’t.
It’s because he expects a lot from you.
More than anyone else.
What?
Sorry...
So short...
Who’d expect anything from this shrimp?
Isn’t height important in basketball?
What?
Let’s leave, Ryota.
Hey long hair!
Leave it!
What?!
I’ll go against you one-on-one anytime, but if you lose...
...you’ll have to shave your head, okay?
Stop right there!
That brat...
Norio.
...let’s crush that kid.
My pleasure.
Shohoku
Egawa Industry
Here!
Why didn’t they pass? He can’t even get out.
Senpai!
Shit!
What the hell?!
Loose ball!
Defense!
Get back!
Let me go out there, damn it!
Fucking losers.
Shohoku
Egawa Industry
Acting like you’re the only one that tried out there.
Ahh... it’s finally over.
From here on I’m retired!
With us older players gone, it’s time
for the reign of terror to begin.
I feel sorry for you guys.
Well, do your best to hang on another year.
Although, I doubt you’ll make it to summer...
...troublemaker
Eh?
Ah? I’m talking about that look.
You looking down on me?
A stubborn bull and a troublemaker.
It’s a match made in heaven.
At least Miyagi can pass the ball.
You’re overthinking.
How about moving your feet more instead?
Kogure.
Yes.
Switch with Sakuragi.
Starting. Red team, get on the court.
Hey pops...
Don’t tell me you subbed out the genius...
... because you’re giving up?
You’re putting Glasses out there so he can play one last game?
Who is Sannoh playing next?
Aiwa Academy. Looks interesting.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Am I the only one that thinks we can still win?
Shohoku
Sannoh
Pops, you still haven’t given up?
Give up?
Once you give up, the game is truly over.
Screen him out!
OK!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Woah! Yeah!
Shohoku
Sannoh
You’re up after this, make it count.
Yes!
They’re too damn tall.
Rebound!
Right here.
What would happen if you took that rebound?
Yamaoh would lose their confidence?
Not that.
First, Sannoh won’t be able to counterattack after the rebound.
Then, Shohoku would get another chance to score.
In other words...
...the two-point loss turns into
a chance for a two-point gain.
Do you understand, Sakuragi?
That’s worth four points!
If you can do that
you’ll be the key to our comeback.
Pull in the ball... Pull in the ball...
It’s filled with my prayers...
I’m counting on you, Sakuragi!
Mine too!
Pull in the ball… pull in the ball…
My prayers too!
What the hell you guys?
What are they doing?
Seriously…
Only plebs like you would come up with this.
That’s fine! So what if we’re plebs?!
You can’t get rebounds with prayers.
Still not yet, pops?
I’m asking if it’s still not my turn yet!
Hurry up! Put me in already!
HANAMICHI!
They’re sending out Sakuragi while this far behind?
That first year doesn’t seem like he can shoot threes.
Good luck, Sakuragi.
Hey, Glasses.
Hanamichi.
I’ve been waiting for you, troublemaker.
Let’s catch up, newbie.
Once you give up, the game is truly over, huh?
Whoa!
What are you doing at a time like this?
What are you—
What are you doing? Get down from there!
That idiot!
“I’m gonna defeat Yamaoh!”
By Genius Sakuragi!
What did you say?!
Are you stupid?
Kick him out!
Get down!
You moron!
I’m sorry.
He only started playing four months ago.
If he does that again, he’ll be ejected.
Heheheh...
How’d you guys like that?
Huh?
Now we have no choice but to win.
Why the long face, Gori?
You don’t think we can win?
What’d you say?
Closing that gap is harder than you think.
Huh?
Fool...
Your basketball logic doesn’t apply to me...
...’cause I’m a newbie.
C’mon! Let’s go guys!
Try your best to keep up with the genius!
Kick him out!
Take him off the court!
What? I can’t hear you!
Hey you guys!
Where are our cheers for victory?
We can’t lose to this annoying crowd!
Cheers for victory?
Ha!
We can do it!
Let’s go!
Not good!
That idiot shot the ball before I figured out a plan!
That jerk!
Alright!
Yeah!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Yeah, that’s it!
That bastard...
Yeah!
The score in the second half is 26 to 2
but they’re not that much better than us.
The momentum will definitely shift our way.
By then if the lead is down to 10 points
we’ll still have a chance!
Akagi, help them!
Yes! Ryota!
Get it together!
We have to seize the momentum ourselves!
Damn it!
A three!
Get in!
Again!
That’s a fake!
Shohoku
Sannoh
He did it!
Sakuragi!
Hanamichi!
Haha, did you all see that?
Amazing, he actually followed instructions!
Well, those two points were given to us.
But the reason I put Sakuragi in...
... wasn’t just to catch rebounds.
Eh?
Let’s get the lead down to 10 points.
Yeah!
Let’s go, let’s go, Shohoku!
Push on, push on, Shohoku!
Defense! Defense!
Damn it!
Boss! You’re holding the ball for too long!
That shot won’t go in.
I knew it!
So high!
Not only that...
He’s quick!
How?
Redhead... Not bad!
Pass it out, Hanamichi!!
National champions...
Offense, charging!
All alone, dan dan!
On your own, dan dan!
All alone, d- huh?
Just stay there on the ground.
No one will blame you.
You’ve already done enough.
It’s too much for you!
It’s impossible to begin with!
Do you think you’re the only one
that’s doing the right thing?
Don’t push your dream of national championships on us.
It’s annoying.
I’ve always wondered, Akagi...
How’s the view looking down on others?
What the hell do you think of us?
Ouch!
Are you ok? Do you need to sub out?
I’m fine.
That’s right...
My dream is already being fulfilled.
Gori’s finally back, about time.
Kawata is Kawata, you are you...
Akagi is Akagi...
I am...
Red team’s ball.
One basket!
Come on.
This guy is at his limit.
Kawata is Kawata, Akagi is Akagi...
And I am...
Who am I?
You don’t wanna beat me?
Shut it.
Say my name...
Who am I...?
Hey!
Is this an after-school special?
This stuff really happens?
I don’t like your crooked eyebrows.
Well, I don’t like your long flowy hair.
Say my name!
Mitsui!
Yeah!
Shohoku
Sannoh
He can barely run ...
Nice! There is only a 10-point difference.
Hey, Miyagi
Go ahead and use me—
Did he say “use”?
Akagi will set the screen for me
I’ll be open...!
If my three-pointers are taken away from me
I would have nothing!
Hey!
Yeah! That’s it!
Micchi!
Right now the only thing I can see is
the hoop!
Let’s go! Offense starts with defense...
Uh... we’re on defense now, right?
Why? He’s obviously exhausted.
Don’t worry about it, Matsumoto!
Let him shoot, let him shoot.
He’s resilient...
But if they focus on threes, it’ll be easier to guard.
We’ll only need to pick up what falls.
That won’t go in!
Look!
Rebound!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Hey you! What’s the matter?
Hey, right over here!
Hey!
Don’t get cocky!
Piece of shit!
You fucking bastard!
Bastard!
Mitsui!
Hey fuck off!
What is this?
It’s like trash...
My heart...
was pounding like crazy...
What happened?
Ryota!
What’s going on?
Shit...
Ryota?
Ryota!
Mom! Ryota woke up!
Are you okay Ryota? Can you hear me?
You’re at the hospital.
Hospital...?
Your bike was destroyed in the crash.
Oh...
The bike...
I saw Okinawa...
What were you thinking?
The doctor said that you’re lucky to be alive.
Can we go a little slower?
What are you saying?
Mr. Former All-Japan Player.
Ah! You’re Ryota, right?
When did you arrive?
You’re all grown up!
How are you?
Granny, who is he?
Oh? Who do we have here?
Sota, that’s so cool!
Ow!
Are they pros?
No, they’re high schoolers
Three-time Inter-High champions...
BASKETBALL
SANNOH
MONTHLY
THE STRONGEST
Sannoh, the Strongest.
Sannoh...
Sota, are you going there?
Might as well do this, right?
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
First, second, third year in middle school...
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
High school...
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
Four years.
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
Representing Okinawa...
Ace player Miyagi Sota!
He’s going in! Aha, watch out!
Double clutch!
It’s in!
He defeated Sannoh the Strongest!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
I’ll beat them!
SANNOH
THE STRONGEST
Sota...
Forgive me...
I don’t know why...
I’m always giving Mom trouble...
If only you were here...
Let’s go!
Intentional foul, white number 4!
Intentional foul?
What?
Nice!
Let’s go!
What happened to your hair?
Don’t tell me... you’re coming back to the team?
Shut up.
I’ve never been good at giving up.
Seriously...?
This is the crucial moment
If we can seize this chance, we’re still in this game.
If we can’t, we don’t deserve to beat Sannoh.
Got it?
Let’s get within 10 points!
Yeah!
Looks like they finally found their rhythm.
Japan’s number one guard... Fukatsu...
Against me?
I gotta match up against this guy?
I’m supposed to be the speedster floor general.
But I always...
...only shrank away.
How so?
You’re always picking fights, aren’t you?
Fukatsu’s been a starter on Sannoh since his first year
I’m gonna go up against that guy...
Isn’t that perfect?
Speedster floor general.
My heart is pounding like crazy.
Really? I had no idea.
You always look so composed.
You’re a pretty good point guard yourself.
Well... not number one in Kanagawa...
Not number two either...
Let’s see...
It’s fine, no need to do that!
Let’s think of what to do when things get tough!
It could be anything.
Right...
For example...
Something like looking at the palm of your hand?
Miyagi seems to be worn out from being on court full-time.
Ryo, make it in!
Shoot carefully!
Aim, shoot, and don’t miss!
Shut up! You’re distracting me!
Alright!
He’s going to be fine.
Yeah!
Ow.
Yes!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Screen! Switch!
Gorilla Dunk!
Shohoku
Sannoh
10-point difference!
Kawata!
Kawata is guarding the Redhead!
Kawata...
Other than you, this is the first guy
that took this many rebounds from me.
Damn it!
What’s got you smiling like that?
Give me everything you’ve got, Fat Gorilla!
Haha!
Got it!
The one who created this rhythm was Sakuragi.
Rebound!
My bad, you were there?
Fat Gorilla!
Oh no! It’s Sawakita!
Good defense Rukawa!
You won’t get through.
Oh?
Stopped it!
Don’t let them make easy passes
Are you sleeping, Fox?
What’d you say?
Hey blowhard.
What?
You talk big about becoming number one in Japan
but you can’t do anything against that Little Monk.
Hmph.
Hey! Are you ignoring me?
Hey, get on defense Sakuragi!
Hey...
Is this all you’ve got?
I’ll crush you.
Bring it on.
Switch!
Kawata!
Yeah!
Huh.
He’s still up here.
Yes! FASTBREAK!
Ahh! Crap!
Lead is down to eight!
Shohoku
Sannoh
They weren’t even on the radar.
That Shohoku...
If that freshmen duo goes on a roll
they’re gonna be a problem yo.
It’ll depend on if we can contain those two.
If they score on us, we’ll just return the favor...
... three times over.
Feed me the ball, Fukatsu!
Let’s go Sannoh! Come on Sannoh!
Shut up!
Let’s go!
Keep your hands up!
Damn! Get back here!
Take this!
Go!
What the—!!
I’ve been waiting, Sawakita!
Super ace!
There’s really someone like this my age?
He probably lived and breathed basketball for 17 whole years.
But...
Haven’t you done the same?
He’s through!
No.
Fukatsu!
Pass it!
He got it!
You dumbass Fox!
Aah! That stupid weird shot again!
That was just a fluke!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Sawakita! Sawakita!
You wanna be the number one player in Japan?
Rukawa.
Shut up.
You can be...
once I’m no longer in Japan.
Ready...
GO!
Don’t screw with me!
Wait up!
I’ve done all there is to do in high school basketball
There’s nothing left for me to prove now.
Please give me the experience that I need.
If there is still anything missing...
...please give it to me.
6, 7, 8, 9, 10...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10...
Three hundred.
Not bad.
One-on-one... You’ll never beat me, Rukawa.
Rukawa out of all people
got taken out like that so easily?
It’s not over.
Hey!
Rebound!
I can’t let that redhead jump.
First, gotta stop him from jumping.
Then, I can just take the ball afterward.
Sannoh
Shohoku
What’s wrong? Are you giving up?
Not yet.
Go! You’re the star player!
You’re not protecting the ball.
Counts! One free throw.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Bastard...
Shohoku
Sannoh
That shitty bastard!
So arrogant.
That’s the number one player in Japan.
He’s still only a second year, same as me.
I wanna see that face cry.
Me too.
Right.
By the way...
Is this the first time we’ve talked?
This was a good game...
Yeah.
It was a good game.
Shohoku was a pretty good team.
Hey!
The five on the court are fighting against amazing players.
The bench must fight till the end too!
Huh?
Shohoku
Sannoh
Yeah!
Does he still not get it?
He can’t win against Sawakita!
What is it Rukawa?
He’s out of options.
Rukawa, 6 seconds left!
Getting close to 30 seconds!
4 seconds left!
Where is he going?
Basket counts!
Yeah!
Coach?
A pass?
Rukawa passed? That Rukawa—
He chose to pass...?
Good call.
In!
Damn!
Pass!
Hmph!
Cover him!
Shit—
Sannoh
Shohoku
Rukawa found his rhythm.
He seems a bit different from usual...
All right, have at it, Rukawa!
Naive!
Yeah! Let’s go!
Shohoku
Sannoh
That’s it!
You rushed over to guard me...
...even though I can’t even lift my arms.
Shit! I knew it, he’s way over his limit!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Three and a half minutes left...
Shohoku
Sannoh
Just 13 points!
Careless!
There!
Yeah! Go!
Come on!
He can’t shoot anymore!
You’re not that lame, right?
Quiet now...
This sound...
...brings me back to life
over and over again!
Sannoh
Shohoku
Yeah!
Sannoh
Shohoku
We’re within 10!
What’s with them?
They’re back at 10 points again?!
What’s up with this?
They’re resilient!
Nice!
Let’s make this possession count!
Defense! Defense!
This guy!
Down to 8 points!
Shohoku
Sannoh
8 points, with two minutes fifty seconds left...
That’s it!
Good!
Smile a little won’t ya!
We have a chance!
Gori.
Huh?
He’s gonna go against Rukawa again.
That guy won’t pass.
Because he’s never lost.
Shit!
Yeah! See that?
My genius plan worked like a charm!
2 minutes and a half!
Shohoku
Sannoh
8 points and the ball is ours!
Gori, we can still do this right?
You guys can do it!
We can win!
Don’t give up!
This guy’s not even a little fazed?
It hit me!
Get it! Please!
Don’t give up...
Don’t give up!
MOVE MICCHI!
Referee timeout!
This is bad...
He’s not moving.
Hey...
Sakuragi!
You did good
for a crappy player.
Who the hell are you calling crappy?!
You’re alive?
Of course I am!
Can you play?
Oh yeah.
Nice one Shohoku!
Make this one count!
Shohoku!
Whos that?
Shohoku! Shohoku!
Shohoku Shohoku!
Shohoku!
How many times do we need to beat them till they give up?
Come on! Get louder! Louder!
What...?
Go for it!
Fadeaway!
Nice!
Not right!
Rebound!
Defense! Defense!
Okay! Let’s go for this one!
Even if it’s tough...
Even if my heart is pounding...
I have to pretend I’m fine.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Fool... Are you still scared of Kawata?
Go sub out...
...if you can’t keep up.
Number 11 again!
Will it be a drive? Or a pass?
You forgot one more thing.
Shohoku
Sannoh
It’s in!
Three-pointer!
Time out, Sannoh!
This is bad, the pain is getting worse.
Does it hurt anywhere Sakuragi?
Nothing, my back’s just a little...
Where on your back?
What kind of pain?
It just pinches a little sometimes.
I’m fine.
This could end your playing career.
Stop running away...
This is it...
Gotta keep this momentum going.
Can you still run?
I can’t lift my arms anymore.
OK. I’ll send the pass to you.
Hey pops, we’ll overtake them, right?
Absolutely.
Sakuragi brought this team rebounding and courage.
Miyagi brought us speed and game sense.
Mitsui once brought us chaos...
... but later brought wisdom and sharpshooting.
Rukawa his explosiveness and will to win.
All these things are added to
the foundation built by Akagi and Kogure.
That is Shohoku.
Honestly, I don’t like any one of you much.
All you guys do is piss me off.
Huh?
But...
But what?
Nevermind...
Thank you, guys...
Huh?
Dumbass, what’d you mean “Thank you”?!
No one’s doing this for you!
I’m doing this for myself!
Hurry up and get on.
Listen up you bastards...
Let’s go!
YEAH!
Alright! Let’s go!
They’re using the size mismatch!
He’s cold as ice!
He should feel the pressure from being pursued!
Kawata’s open!
That’s right, our opponent is still...
Sannoh the Strongest!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Full-court press!
Ryota!
Coach Domoto...
We have no intention of winning by playing safe.
We’re going to fight it out till the end.
Because that’s the playstyle of this undefeated team!
Miyagi!
Ryo!
Ryota! Break through!
Show them what you’ve got!
Mom, do you want a small piece?
Yeah.
Of course!
Since I’m skinny, I’ll take the rest.
Did you say something?
Nothing...
Here, a big slice for the star.
Isn’t your piece bigger?
You can have the chocolate plaque.
Brothers having the same birthday is pretty rare.
py Birthday Ryota!
That means we are special.
What time tomorrow?
Ryota, what time are you leaving tomorrow?
For Hiroshima, Inter-High.
6 AM.
So early!
Mom, did you hear that? He said 6 AM!
Ryota is 17 years old now...
... what about Sota?
Hey!
Let’s see...
20 years old.
If he was still alive.
20 years old huh...
Always 3 years younger
even though he’s older than Sota ever was.
Let’s put up a photo of Sota!
I feel like I’ll forget his face.
It’s been 8 years.
Yeah.
Happy 17th birthday.
Thank you.
Dear Mother,
Every year on this day I think about
how sorry I am for being the one who's alive.
Mother?
What’s this?
Dear Mother,
I’m sorry for constantly causing problems
and always making you worry.
You must really dislike basketball, right?
Because it reminds you of Sota...
Even then...
You have never once asked me to quit basketball.
When I played minibasket,
it made me really happy that you went to see my games.
Sota is amazing!
He already scored 20 points in the first half!
Your brother is amazing, isn’t he?
Well... that’s why he’s the captain.
Are you gonna grow up to be like him?
He will if he practices lots, right?
In a world without Sota,
basketball was my only reason to keep going.
Thank you for letting me keep playing.
Stop it! Why are you throwing it away?
Mom! This is serious!
I don’t know...
What should I do?
I’m glad that I was able to keep playing.
Tomorrow, I will be standing in the place
that Sota wanted to reach.
Hey, don’t record me!
It’s ok, keep playing!
You have to get lower, like this.
Shut up!
You can do it!
Damn it!
You’re losing your edge, yo.
What should I do
to get through these giants?
Go...
Go!
GO! RYOTA!
Dribbling is the only way...
... shorties can survive on the court!
Good job Ryota!
Defense! Defense!
That’s it!
Get in there!
No basket! After the foul!
Okay, it’s up to you Akagi!
Number 4 is doing the free throw.
It’s my free throw, Sakuragi.
No basket? Screw that...
The genius’s... slam dunk...
I was supposed to beat you someday, Rukawa.
Wait a minute... Don’t sub me out...
He got hurt when he was going after the loose ball.
W-where?!
Ayako, please don’t say it.
His back.
His back...?
My career as a player...
Does this mean... it’s over for me?
Does this mean...
...I can’t play basketball anymore?
Do you like basketball?
I love it, because I’m an athlete.
Siblings?!
Place the ball in!
Screen out!
Good, That’s it!
One last shot!
The left hand only supports the ball...
Rebound King’s national debut!
Shohoku
Sannoh
Yes!
Nice!
Hanamichi.
I’ve been waiting for you, troublemaker.
Damn it...
Damn... it...
Make it in.
Akagi.
Yes!
Substitution please!
Hanamichi!
Hey!
Sakuragi!
What do you think you’re doing?
Sakuragi...
Sakuragi.
Ryo.
I’ll be right there.
Gori.
Until then protect the post for me!
Sakuragi Hanamichi!
Don’t be ridiculous! Get over here!
See? You can barely stand!
Apologies, please cancel the substitution.
Hey, pops!
Sakuragi...
I must confess...
I noticed something was wrong right away.
But even though I noticed, I didn’t sub you out.
Because I wanted to keep watching
your playing improve more and more.
I’ve failed as a coach.
I almost did something I would’ve regretted my whole life.
Sannoh
Shohoku
1 minute left!
Let’s cheer them on together, Sakuragi!
Pops, when was your moment of glory?
Was it during the All-Japan Tournament?
For me...
For me, it’s RIGHT NOW!
Red! Pushing!
Hey.
You’re an eyesore, just standing there.
If you’re gonna come on, then come on.
Idiot.
Player substitution.
He’s coming back in?
There’s the Redhead!
Go wild out there!
We’ve been waiting for you!
Hanamichi...
Are you ok?
What’s with the serious faces?
You all must have felt lonely without me here.
It’s a fitting handicap for this genius
when facing someone like Yamaoh.
You said so before right, Gori?
They’re just stepping stones, those guys!
Why do I have to hear this from a newbie like you?
What?
Shohoku
Sannoh
Hey!
Come here!
Those guys will full-court press again.
They’ll be coming for me.
Rukawa.
When that time comes you take the ball...
... if you can go for it then go.
Okay.
Boss, keep an eye out for Rukawa.
Got it.
Listen...
We can do this.
Boss.
1,2,3...
WIN!
Bring it on, Sannoh!
Alright!
Come!
They’re serious!
They really think they can score 5 points in 1 minute?
Let’s go Shohoku!
Defense! Defense!
Shohoku
Sannoh
They’re targeting him on purpose!
Fool!
Let’s go, Mikio!
Wh-
-at?!
Let’s go! Rukawa!
Yes! Stopped him!
A fake!
Basket counts! 3 points!
Foul! White number 6, pushing.
One free throw.
Shohoku
Sannoh
Shohoku!
Great hustle to get open, Mitsui!
I’m so glad I chose Shohoku...!
From here on it’ll be a battle of spirits.
How much determination they have.
How far they’re willing to trust their own playing.
Shohoku
Sannoh
One point difference!
47, 46, 45, 44...
Defend to the death!
Don’t let them score!
You can do it!
Sakuragi, you can do it!
Miyagi...
Rukawa...
Mitsui, you can do it!
You can do it...
Akagi!
Go!
Give it back.
STOP HIM! Hurry up and stop him!
It’s over!
Sannoh
Shohoku
Yeah!
Hmph!
YEAH!
How was Sannoh?
Strong.
Scary.
Ryota...
What...?
Welcome back.
I’m home.
Have you gotten taller?
Of course not, it’s been only four days.
Here.
It’s Sota’s.
Ryota!
Welcome back Ryota!
Hey! What are you doing?
Hey you— I said what are you doing—
Hey!
You’ve done it now!
Hey hey I said sto—
Here!
Whoa!!
Wait—come here you!
We’ll rise again.
One day, having experienced defeat
will become a source of great strength.
Please give me the experience that I need.
What are some of the differences after you came here?
It’s much more physical.
I feel like I’m surrounded by Kawata clones.
What will be your focus in this team?
I’m on the shorter side so I’m playing as a point guard.
I still have a long way to go.
I’m getting ahead of myself.
Thank you for your hard work coming all this way.